# 福建·厦门
Fujian, Xiamen
# 一炉炉的都是 鸭子
Look at the clay pots! These are all ducks.
# 盖上盖子
Close the lids
# 姜母鸭
Jiangmu Ya (Ginger Duck Stew)
# 站在这个你都能闻到
You can even smell it over here
# 鸭油和姜片的这种混合香味
The mixed aroma of duck fat and sliced ginger
# 感觉在这儿都要流口水了
I feel that I’m gonna drool here
# 雪鱼今天来到的是一家做姜母鸭的熟食店
Today I’m in a deli that mainly serves Jiangmu duck.
# 来的正巧 他们正忙着炖鸭子
Just in time, they’re busy making duck stews.
# 走在附近 光这肉香 都能把我吸引过来
Even just walking by, I can be drawn here by the smell of the meat.
# 这边是两间屋子
The two rooms here
# 都是用来做鸭子的
are all used to make duck stews
# 好多
There are so many of them!
# 别人卖鸭子都是一只只地卖
Others sell duck one at a time
# 在这里是一排排地卖 一轮轮地卖
They sell ducks by rounds here
# 要是赶上逢年过节
If it’s the holidays
# 人不休息 炉子也甭想休息
cooks can’t rest, nor do the stoves
# 刚才小哥说 这边最忙的时候
The cook just told me, the busiest time here
# 一天能够做七八百只鸭子
they could cook 700-800 ducks in a day
# 我说是从早上 一直做到下午吗
I asked him did they cooked a whole day from morning to afternoon
# 他说 通宵
He said they continued cooking overnight
# 仔细看 你会发现
If you look closely you’ll find that
# 做姜母鸭（盐鸭）的装置是特别的
The equipment used to cook the Jiangmu Ya(Ginger duck stew) or salt duck is special
# 下面是炉火 中间有一层隔热的（盐）
There’s a layer of salt used to insulate heat between the stove and the pot
# 上面才是砂锅
and clay pots on top
# 鸭子放进砂锅之前
Before putting into the pots
# 都是要进行提前腌制的
the ducks have to be marinated
# 然后才是一整只鸭子和姜母放在砂锅里
then they were put into the pots with the gingers
# 盖上盖子 足足要炖一个多小时
They are going to be stewed for an hour with the lid closed.
# 你好 帮我拿半只吧
Hi! Can I have half of the duck?
# 好
Sure.
# 透过袋子 你能隐隐约约看到鸭油和鸭汤
You can vaguely see the duck fat and juice through the plastic bag
# 这个时候 有碗米饭真的会很香
It will be very nice to have a bowl of rice with it
# 看我的白米饭 配鸭肉来吃
Look at my white rice. I’m going to eat it with the duck
# 鸭子炖的时间很长了
The duck has been stewed for a very long time
# 压在下面的姜片都被炖没型了
The ginger slices underneath have turned into mush
# 肉呢 特别软烂
Meat is really soft
# 鸭肉很容易从骨头上撕扯下来
The meat easily falls off the bones
# 它这个鸭子吃起来 干香干香的
It tastes so good, so rich.
# 吃的时候呢 米饭上还会粘些鸭油
The duck fat sticks to the rice when you eat it
# 啊 真的是下饭神器
OMG, it’s so good when eating with rice.
# 福建·漳州
Zhangzhou, Fujian,
# 咱们这是出来吃早餐
We are here to eat breakfast
# 但是在我的对面 我发现
But I found out that across the street
# 他们的夜场都没有散
They are still continuing their nightlife.
# 走了10多分钟 总算来到了卤面店
Over 10 minutes of walking, we’ve finally arrived at the heavy-gravy noodle restaurant
# 我们现在要进去
We are going in now
# 点一碗热气腾腾的面来吃
to order a bowl of hot noodles
# 知道为什么来这么早吗
Do you know why we are here so early?
# 因为来得早 料多丰富
Because if you come early, the sides are still in stock
# 想吃什么点什么
You can order whatever you want
# 在这儿吃吗
For here?
# 豆芽 香菜要不要
Do you want bean sprouts and cilantro
# 我这边刚说完 阿姨就揪了一把碱面
I barely finished my sentence, and she had already grabbed a handful of alkaline noodles
# 放在开水当中 捞一下过水
Blanch in boiling water
# 短短几秒钟 面条脱胎换骨
Just for a few seconds, the noodles are transformed
# 做好的面
Cooked noodles
# 浇上猪骨熬出来的浓郁的卤汁来调味
Pour in the rich braising broth made from pork bones
# 再按自己的心意 选一些配菜
Then choose the sides you want
# 真的会让这碗面 香上加香
It will really improve the flavor of the noodles
# 咔嚓 咔嚓
(scissors chopping)
(still chopping)
# 卤煮  剪肉时候也是这样咔嚓咔嚓
Braised dishes. Meat is also chopped like this
# 没有食物 刀也不停
The chopping never stops
# 雪鱼的口味 让人捉摸不透
My taste is a mystery
# 它的面条也是这种碱水面
This noodle is also alkaline noodle
# 就是很容易咬断
It’s very easy to bite apart
# 吃面条的时候 还会顺带吃卤子
I’m also eating the sides while eating the noodles
# 它这个是
How does it taste like?
# 咸的
salty
# 我们加了鱼丸 猪皮 豆腐
We added fish ball, pigskin, and tofu
# 这个是我专门要的鱼丸
This fishball is special order by me
# 很喜欢吃鱼丸这种香中带甜的味道
I like the salty taste with sweetness
# 加了豆腐呢 主要是因为
I added tofu mainly because
# 豆腐能吸收汤汁
Tofu can absorb the soup
# 这样会让豆腐更饱满一些
This will make the tofu taste fuller
# 这一大早
In the early
# 咱们这碗面加的料还是很丰富的
We added too many sides in the noodle
# 但是和桌子上摆的料比起来
But comparing with the sides on the table
# 可能只是它的几分之一了
it’s only a portion of them
# 像大肠 炸肉这些
Like pig intestine and fired meat
# 也都是大家比较喜欢吃的
they’re faviortes for everyone
# 我要猪皮最重要的一个原因就是
The most important reason that I choose pigskin is that
# 它刚拿出来 看着让人很有食欲
It’s freshly cooked, looks very tempting
# 想一想刚才这碗面端上来的时候
Think back to the noodles when it’s just served
# 汤汁还是很浓郁的
The soup was very thick
# 现在有点稀了
Now it’s a little bit thinner
# 但是依然挡不住
but still
# 它的这种海鲜的鲜甜的味道
The umami and sweetness of the seafood are still here
# 现在满屋子都是吸溜面条的声音
Now the whole room is filled with the sound of noodle slurping
# 但这个声音再大
But no matter how loud it is
# 也抵不过旁边的阿姨拿剪刀
they are never gonna cover the chopping sounds of the scissors
# 咔嚓咔嚓咔嚓 剪这些材料的声音
the chopping of the sides
# 真是神奇的剪刀手
Her movements of the scissors are amazing
# 你看早上来吃饭 大家都比较赶时间
When eating in the morning, everyone is kind of short on time
# 早一点的话 可能没有那么多人
If we come earlier, there won’t be this many people
# 但是晚几分钟 人都会挤在早餐店的门口
But just a few minutes later, the entrance will be packed
# 现在呢 上学的和上班的人渐渐多了
Now, more and more students and people who are heading to work are here
# 早餐店也变得更加忙碌了
the restraunt is getting busier
# 伴着咔嚓咔嚓的声音
with the chopping sound
# 我们也结束了今天的视频
We are putting this video to an end
# ( ^_^ )/~~拜拜
bye bye
# 大早上起来就吃了20多块钱的饭
Spent 20 yuan for breakfast in the early morning
# 是不是有点太奢侈了
Is it too luxrious?
# 感觉中午也得少吃点吧 要不
Maybe eat less for lunch, or else
# 按这个速度长下去
growing in this speed
# 也重不少呢
I’m gonna put on too much weight